Scott Allan

Portland, OR 97201 | 603.275.5557 | sallan306@gmail.com

SUMMARY

Dedicated worker with 5+ years of service industry experience. Has worked multiple front of house positions, has a well rounded grasp of proper hospitality services, and promotes customer satisfaction. Values knowledge of proper sales techniques for raising customer's check averages while simultaneously enhancing their dining experience. Trained on proper evaluation of wines and spirits, can properly identify acidity, tannic structure, and notes of flavor in wines. Past military experience has taught many lifelong lessons on work ethic and behavior in a professional setting.

EDUCATION

- Full Stack Web Development Bootcamp: University of Texas // January 2019
- Associates of Applied Sciences: Community College of the Air Force // // December 2018
- Emergency Medical Technician Certification: Air Force // September 2014

EXPERIENCE

Air Force National Guard // Emergency Medical Technician // Houston, TX // May 2012 - Jan 2019

- Laboratory Manager, facilitated over 9000 blood draws across 4 years.
- Supervisor of 4 troops, aided in their career development and success.
- Provided humanitarian support to over 10,000 civilians across the US.

Searsucker // Server, Bartender, Lead Expo // Austin, TX // June 2015 - July 2018

- High-end hospitality and customer experience.
- Taught me the customs and courtesies of working at an upscale establishment.
- Learned how to stay accurate and adaptable in a fast paced environment.
- Hosted large catered events for international banks, Netflix, and HBO.

Trudy's Tex Mex // Server // Austin, TX // April 2014 - June 2015

- High volume restaurant with no support staff, learned how to comfortably manage 10 tables at once.
- Learned to appreciate and distinguish authentic Mexican cuisine from Tex-Mex.

Tondee's Tavern // Server // Savannah, GA // Jan 2013 - Feb 2014

- Across from an international hotel, learned how to communicate with customers from all over the world.
- Learned how much I enjoyed Seafood, particularly raw oysters.